spokesmanreview.com 2017-11-20

# Privacy policy | The Spokesman-Review

### Privacy policy

This privacy policy applies to Cowles Publishing Company d/b/a SR Media Group, along with its affiliates and subsidiaries. The policy covers our practices in connection with The Spokesman-Review newspaper, our websites (spokesman.com, nwprepsnow.com, spokane7.com, spokesmanjobs.com, spokesmanauto.com, spokesmanhomes.com, spokesmanclassifieds.com, bizfindernw.com, kissthebridenw.com), our smartphone and tablet apps and mobile sites.

#### Information contained in this document:

  * What information we gather about you.
  * How we gather the information.
  * What we do with the information.
  * How you can change, update or delete your personal information.
  * How you can learn of changes to our privacy policy.
  * How to contact us.

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

We collect personal information such as your name, contact information and credit card information _only when you choose to provide it._ For example, we may collect this information when you subscribe to the Spokesman-Review, request a newsletter, or register on our website. We also collect information that you provide when you comment on articles, submit photos or other content or enter a contest.

#### NON PERSONAL INFORMATION

This is information that technology collects and aggregates but does not identify you personally. This information may include your internet provider, the type of device you use to access our websites and tracking of the content you read on our websites. It may also track the time of use and duration on our site, your location information such as your computer’s IP address and any information stored in cookies and other technologies. 

To learn more about cookies and how to control or delete them, we recommend you read on or visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) or [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). Deleting cookies may impair the functionality of this site and your enjoyment of it. 

**How we gather the information.**

**You may choose to provide information to us.** In order to take advantage of our services, you may choose to provide your contact information, billing information or other personal information. If you contact The Spokesman-Review, we may collect information about the interaction.

**We use technology.** We may use cookies and other technologies to gather non personal information about your use of our site. . Deleting cookies may impair the functionality of this site and your enjoyment of it.

**We allow third parties to gather information.** Some advertisements and services on our websites are operated by third party vendors who assist us in understanding how users use our sites. This helps us to improve our sites and provide a better user experience. We may engage third party vendors to enable us to provide readers customized content based on their use of our website.

Some sections of our website may direct you to a third party website. Third parties collection and use of data is in compliance with their own privacy policies. 

Actions taken through Facebook, Twitter, Google+ or other third parties are governed by the privacy policies of the third party

**What we do with the information.**

We do not sell, license or rent the information we collect without your permission except as stated in this policy or as required by law.

We use your Personal Information to operate Spokesman.com and other affiliated sites and to provide products and services you request.

We use the information to improve our sites and your experience.

We disclose your opt-out information to third parties in order to comply with your requests.

We may use the information to communicate with you about your current products or services. We may communicate with you about changes to our products or to discuss your subscription. We may communicate with you about new features, services, products and offers. These products and services may be from us or our partners and affiliates, advertisers or other third parties. You may opt out of any primarily commercial message at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the email.

#### REGISTRATION

All users who wish to access news content on Spokesman.com are required to register after viewing a certain number of articles must agree with the terms of our [Service Agreement.](http://www.spokesman.com/service-agreement/) Spokesman.com, along with several other affiliated sites, requires all registrants to provide a valid e-mail address and a personal password. Users who want unlimited online access to content on Spokesman.com will, along with being required to purchase unlimited access, be required to provide additional personal information, including, but not limited to, home address, home telephone number, home ZIP code, newspaper subscriber account number (when applicable), as well as other billing and credit card information. Other demographic information (e.g., country, ZIP code, age, sex, job title, etc.) may also be requested from time to time.

**Your consent**

Currently we use the following cookies and we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which means that we assume you are happy with this usage.

Google Analytics – we use this to understand how our Website is being used in order to improve the user experience. User data is all anonymous. You can find out more about Google’s position on privacy as regards its analytics service at <http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html>

#### AP NEWS REGISTRY

Our Website uses services provided by AP News Registry. AP News Registry collects content usage information and may use cookies in conjunction with this activity. Your continued readership of the Site means you accept the privacy policy of the AP News Registry. Please refer to the [ AP News Registry privacy policy for further information.](http://www.apnewsregistry.com/privacycenter/servicepolicy.aspx)

#### STATISTICAL ANALYSIS AND BANNER ADVERTISING

SPOKESMAN.COM may perform statistical analyses of user behavior in order to measure interest in the various areas of our sites (for product development purposes) and to inform advertisers as to how many users have seen or "clicked" their advertising banners. We also may use demographic and preference information to allow advertising banners on our Web sites to be targeted, in aggregate, to the users for whom they are most pertinent. This means that users see advertising that is most likely to interest them, and advertisers send their messages to people who are most likely to be receptive, improving both the viewer's experience and the effectiveness of the ads. In these statistical analyses and banner advertisement targeting, we will disclose information to third parties only in aggregate form. Personal information about you as an individual user or viewer of our site will not be provided to any third party without your consent, except under the circumstances described in Compliance with Legal Process below.

#### DATA SECURITY

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online.

#### COMPLIANCE WITH LEGAL PROCESS

SPOKESMAN.COM may disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of SPOKESMAN.COM web services; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public. (Among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions.)

**How you can change or update or your personal information.**

_Changes to your account information: You may change or update your information by logging in to your account in our Subscriber Services center or by contacting our customer service department a t[circ@spokesman.com](mailto:circ@spokesman.com)_

**Opting out:** If you wish to discontinue receiving promotional email from us or one of our marketing partners, simply click on the unsubscribe option at the bottom of the email. To opt out of telephone solicitations, you may notify us by calling [800.338.8801](tel:+18003388801) or by email at [circ@spokesman.com](mailto:circ@spokesman.com).

**How you can learn of changes to our privacy policy.**

We reserve the right to update or change this policy at anytime. Please check here periodically for changes. 

* * *

**How to contact us:**

If you have questions or comments regarding our information or privacy practices, you may contact us by e-mail at [information@spokesman.com](mailto:information@spokesman.com). Or by phone at [509.459.5000](tel:+15094595000)

SPOKESMAN.COM and all affiliated websites are maintained by _**The Spokesman-Review**_ and owned by Cowles Publishing Company, 999 West Riverside Avenue, Spokane, WA 99201. 

S1351932.DOCX

* * *
